Bezabeh Ambaw

Graduated by AAS, Network Security Engineer and **BS Cyber Security**

After I participated in setting the Design and setup competition network scheme using various MS Windows Server and Linux OS for Pacific Rim Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition (PRCCDC) occurred at Highline College, work as IT lab technician, did IT internship at Inbia, and start working at AWS, I felt confident by my knowledge, experience and really interested to join a company which can give me full time job opportunity for IT, cybersecurity and network engineering related position.

shebela88@gmail.com

206-466-9867

SeaTac, USA 👂

EDUCATION

Graduated by Network Security engineering

Highline College Des Moines WA

01/2015 - 06/2017

USA

Cyber Security and Digital Forensic Highline College Des Moines, WA

07/2019 - Present

WORK EXPERIENCE

Network Development Engineer

Amazon Web service(AWS)>>s.com

08/2019 - Present

Seattle

Achievements/Tasks

- applied port reservation on router for BGP peering with other ISP
- create CM and push them to the router after approved by L1 and L2 team based on AZOTD
- worked on Drive scaling of current network designs to meet the demand of our customers

SKILLS

troubleshooting

Documentation

Excellent Customer service experiance

Hardening Microsoft Windows Servers and workstations

Configure and secure network

Basic Power-Shell, Linux scripting, python scripting

Setting Active directory within MS windows 2008,2012 and 2016 server

Penetration testing by using Kali Linux, Nmap, Wireshark and Metasploit

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Port reservation (08/2019 – Present)

ORGANIZATIONS

AWS

CERTIFICATES FROM HIGHLINE COLLEGE AND CTPE

Certified COMPTIA A+ and CISCO CCNA from Highline College (06/2017)

Certified LAN OPERATN and CISCO CCENT from Highline College (06/2017)

Mile 2 Penetration Testing Engineer from CTPE (03/2017)

Network Admin and Security , Highline College (06/2017)

LANGUAGES

English **Amharic**

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Internship

Inabia Solutions and Consulting

01/2019 - 06/2019

Redmond, WA

Achievements/Tasks

- Applied type 1 and 2 Virtualization and did research about cloud service for better Cloud migration.
- Participating in Software Defined Networking (SDN) Project.
- Installed and configured OpenDaylight, Network controller and Mininet, network emulator on top of Ubuntu 18.04 Machine.
- Integrated OpenDaylight with Mininet and showed POC of creating network Topology, data collection and storage.
- Troubleshoot computer problems. Determines source and solution to computer problem (hardware, software, user and access.
- Configured peripheral devices to the network.
- Setup Active directory Domain controller on Windows 2008, 2012 and 2016 server.
- Deployed Linux and windows machine from template in v Sphere environment for Project use.

Contact: Wajid Hassan (supervisor) – 410 603 4767

Pacific Rim Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition (PRCCDC) Internship Highline College

05/2017 - 09/2017

Achievements/Tasks

- Designed the company network that will be used in the simulation for the computation
- set up MS windows server and Linux OS and make in use for computation
- do research and make the operating system vulnerable and make those who compute to harden the system
- setup virtual cloud environment by using ESXI server and VMWare for computation

Contact: Amelia Phillips

Computer lab Technician Highline College

04/2017 - 11/2017

Des Moines WA

Achievements/Tasks

- Setup computers and installed software for various applications and programs and make ready for student use.
- Tested computer lab's peripheral device(printer) and computers working properly.
- Created user login account for new students.
- Keep records of computer lab requirements and supply.
- Troubleshooted computer hardware and software issue.
- Patch lab computers with new software updated.

Contact: Sheelan - sshamdeen@highline.edu

INTERESTS

Soccer

Information Technology Ted talk